<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Creative Postures]]></title><description><![CDATA[Moron's Memoir]]></description><link>https://www.moronsmemoir.com/blog</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 20:36:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.moronsmemoir.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[The Weekly Vitamin with S.A. Thomas: Wall Street Wisdom &#38; Staten Island Stories]]></title><description><![CDATA[From the Desk of a Wall Street Moron Quote of the Week: "If something can corrupt you, you're corrupted already." - Bob Marley Haiku of...]]></description><link>https://www.moronsmemoir.com/post/the-weekly-vitamin-with-s-a-thomas-wall-street-wisdom-staten-island-stories</link><guid isPermaLink="false">67adedc2d942be1dff9dafb4</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:17:32 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Steven Thomas</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>From the Desk of a Wall Street Moron</h2>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Quote of the Week: &quot;If something can corrupt you, you&apos;re corrupted already.&quot; - Bob Marley</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Haiku of the Moment:  </p>
<p>Jump off the ledge dear,</p>
<p>One of a kind and still trips,</p>
<p>Where did you go fear?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Song of the Week: &quot;Rosa Parks&quot; –Outkast</p>
<p><br /></p>
<h2>Trading Up Your Life: A Moron&apos;s Meditation</h2>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Well, since I&apos;m a writer, I figured I would write. Right? What could go wrong? This is the first attempt at a weekly data dump of Organic Intelligence, the type we all possess. Unscrambling the eggs of anxiety is a lot of work these days. It&apos;s a bit more involved than scrolling up, down, left, and right. Write? Yes, that&apos;s what I said. But what did she say? The supercomputer likes things to be streamlined and easy, so reading this may bother that microchip on your shoulders. Maybe that is the point. Pushing through limits helps gain control back of your life.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Just one year ago, I was out of work, blackballed by an industry, a baby on the way (that&apos;s why we sip Tanqueray), and broke as a joke. Don&apos;t believe me? I&apos;ve got the bank statements to prove it. My negatively hit U4 is a public record for anyone who wants to go dumpster diving. This was the reward I received for 18 years of loyalty with one company. I&apos;m not reliving that trauma any longer thanks to the ability to write. Right? Wrong. Even though I have grown and pushed past the past, does that mean that the past has passed? Yes and no. Wisdom comes from experience, and experience comes from making choices, and yeah, some of those aren&apos;t going to be the right ones. That&apos;s part of the game, my friends.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<h2>Pro Tips from a Wall Street Survivor</h2>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Anyway, where was I? On the wrong side of the tracks, but I avoided the oncoming train in the nick of time. Plenty of nicks though — has anyone seen my nicotine? I enjoy playing with words and my still-developing belief around their ability to be self-medicinal. The Self-Help world is full of Erudites and Charlatans. It&apos;s a menagerie of beasts and burdens, and I&apos;ve realized we&apos;re all just Rolling Stones trying to avoid the Jagged edge. (Sidenote: Having three kids gives me the right to be as punny as I wish. #dadjokes4eva)</p>
<p><br /></p>
<h2>Real Talk About Real Success</h2>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Agency, my friends, is not just how I trade convertible bonds for a living — it&apos;s how I choose to live. With the agency to make decisions, to actively engage with my perspectives and realize that most of the thoughts I have have been given to me. By the world, by my genes, and maybe that smell is coming from my jeans. (Hun, can you wash this for me?)</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>And joking or not, we could all use a good washing. So I&apos;m here. Not to wash your dirty-ass car, bro — that&apos;s your job. But I will show you some steps and moves I&apos;ve undertaken to clean my own. And hun, my shit is just as grimy as yours. There is NO holier-than-thou shit here. I&apos;m not a motivational speaker; I&apos;m a speaker of motivation because I need it. When I stammer on about Gratitude as medicine for the mind, it&apos;s because I needed that stuff. That was the junk to get me off of the junk.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Look around, see how much junk you have in your life. Or just keep scrolling and pretend it ain&apos;t there. If you&apos;re of the latter, then take your ladder and climb another building. This one is for those who like to take the stairs. Ever notice that it&apos;s the ones who take the stairs that live the longest? Have fun on the elevator, my friends — I&apos;ll surely see you at the top. Got a LOT of calories to burn here.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Stevey Ponders...</p>
<p>People will die when you least expect it. Get used to it, and still realize you&apos;ll never get used to it.</p>
<p>Kids are Medicine. Why don&apos;t we bring kindergarten classes to the nursing homes? But I&apos;m the Moron.</p>
<p>If you want to create tomorrow, you should have started yesterday.</p>
<p>Sky&apos;s the limit and death is the doorstep. The choice only helps so much.</p>
<p>Life ain&apos;t fair, but it sure is fun. If you&apos;re reading this, you&apos;re doing something right.</p>
<p>So pumped for Doechii to win Rap Album of the year. That girl is special, and I think the next stage in hip-hop history may be written by the females. Hot Take Alert. BUT, those spots have to be earned, and that is yet to be seen. NostraThomas predicts.</p>
<p>Let&apos;s not let &quot;I remember A Guy&quot; be replaced with &quot;My A.I. Says&quot;....</p>
<p>H2: The Truth About Wall Street Lies</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Taught to Lie — <em>Big Thought alert</em>: We are taught to lie from an early age. No?! Have you ever told your kid to be polite because company was coming over? You basically told them to withhold their honest emotions because someone else is in the space and that&apos;s the customary thing to do. I get it. It&apos;s still lying.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Why do we lie to ourselves so often? Oh, I&apos;m sure you&apos;re different, but I&apos;d like to be more honest, if I&apos;m being honest. Maybe that politeness has to go?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Stevey Ponders is a cool-ass name if I don&apos;t say so myself. (You did, jackass.)</p>
<p><br /></p>
<h2>Trading Up Your Mental Health</h2>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Being your best when things are at their worst — that&apos;s the key. Tragedy cannot turn to triumph without us coming together with love and compassion during moments of crisis. This is where the time becomes the moment and we get to find out who we are. Pay attention to those moments, without judgment, and with an open mind. Small tweaks can lead to the highest peaks. Being accountable is among the strongest habits one can develop.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>It&apos;s a bit like walking on the beach: You may see this wonderfully gigantic rock that has interesting crevices, or you may stab your foot on a cracked seashell. This is my promise to you.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<h2>A Wall Street Survivor&apos;s Gratitude</h2>
<p><br /></p>
<p>They say if you love what you&apos;re doing, you never work a day in your life. For most of my W2 life then, I haven&apos;t been in love. I&apos;ve been in like, and I&apos;ve definitely been in lust, but love? Nah. I love the dough, but love is more than just looks. It&apos;s not just the T+A that turns a wonderful weekend into a lifetime commitment. That&apos;s something else entirely, and that takes patience and commitment.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>I find time and solace in the art of word, and now with the ability and effort to share that art of word, I am not working. I do not expect to be understood because I myself am not totally understood. I am cool being imperfectly trying. I am really grateful for the awareness of the power of words, as they have been around me for so long that, like wallpaper, I forgot they were there. But they are. Hey bud! I&apos;m gonna be playing more with these words, and like an old pal, I expect we are going to get on just fine. Trouble? Nah, what could possibly cause any trouble?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>With Gratitude,</p>
<p>S.A. Thomas</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wall Street Leadership Lessons: From Mope to Managing Director | Authority Magazine Feature]]></title><description><![CDATA[The broken clock strikes again! From the backroom to the fairy tale, I’ve seen a lot in my day. That’s why I was enthused to be able to...]]></description><link>https://www.moronsmemoir.com/post/wall-street-leadership-lessons-from-mope-to-managing-director-authority-magazine-feature</link><guid isPermaLink="false">679979a23abb92803383d4ae</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:43:50 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Steven Thomas</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">The broken clock strikes again! From the backroom to the fairy tale, I’ve seen a lot in my day. That’s why I was enthused to be able to speak to Authority Magazine about some of my experiences in the Finance Industry. Pro Tip: Some stains don’t come out. Preview it below, </span></span><u><a href="https://medium.com/authority-magazine/author-steven-thomas-on-5-things-you-need-to-be-a-highly-effective-c-level-leader-of-a-fintech-21cf225b2248" target="_blank"><span style="color: rgb(17, 85, 204);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">read it over hea</span></span></a></u><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">, or if you have devolved into visuals only, </span></span><u><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-fG2tpd_-Rk&t=2s" target="_blank"><span style="color: rgb(17, 85, 204);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">take a look at this video on my Youtube channel over here</span></span></a></u><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">. </span></span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<h2><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"><strong>From Staten Island Snow Shoveler to Wall Street Hustler</strong></span></span></h2>
<p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">Since I am marketing a book on how to succeed on Wall st, it was a good synergy to be able to talk about what it takes to be successful in finance. I told them, if you are looking for financial advice, I’m not your guy. But success in Finance is about much more than Dollar Signs. It&apos;s about perspective, more than market analysis and yield to maturity. It&apos;s about maturing to be able to yield something positive. The work ethic comes from hunger and guidance, so if it&apos;s shoveling that feeds that fire of intrinsic motivation, then I feed it. I walk backwards into all my problems now, Ass first, saving the best for last. </span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">For whatever reason, the smarter the IQ usually, the lower the EQ. This is where being a Moron has helped me out the most. It wasn’t about the fancy degree or the whale on your belt. Success comes from  knowing what you don’t know, and being able and willing to admit it. I am pitching Gratitude and Humility, and I throw it over the middle every time. And if that snow needs melting, I get in the sauna to heat it up. </span></span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<h2><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"><strong>Five Keys to Financial Success and Survival Tactics</strong></span></span></h2>
<p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">In my Authority Magazine interview, I broke down the real keys to succeeding in finance without losing your soul:</span></span></p>
<ol>
  <li><p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"><strong>Learn to Love the Punch</strong></span></span><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">: Every setback is a setup for a comeback. What doesn’t snap the rubber band, propels it forward.Getting punched in the face allows you to confront your own mind in a unique way. </span></span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"><strong>Build Trust Like a Brick Wall</strong></span></span><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">: One solid decision, one kept promise at a time. Without trust, you&apos;re just another guy in an expensive suit making empty promises.</span></span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"><strong>Know Your Worth</strong></span></span><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">: Either you are setting the price or its being set on you. I learned this shoveling driveways, making bonds 2ways. White Glove Premium service commands premium rates. Don&apos;t let anyone tell you differently.</span></span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"><strong>Embrace Discomfort</strong></span></span><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">: Buckle-up Buttercup, this ride doesn&apos;t always go where you think-or want. But once you’ve strapped in for the ride, accept it and learn to adapt. Adaptation is the superpower of the successful. Unless you wanna go the way of the dinosaur. </span></span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"><strong>Create REALationships</strong></span></span><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">: Not connections, not networks - real, human relationships. In this case technology is not your friend. From Eye contact to a Handshake and Live Concerts to Shared mixtapes, be a Real guy. Be imperfect and fallible. Yea, that whole thinking backwards thing again. </span></span></p><p><br /></p></li>
</ol>
<h2><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"><strong>Beyond the Bottom Line: A New Movement in Finance</strong></span></span></h2>
<p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">But here&apos;s where it gets interesting. When they asked about what movement I&apos;d want to inspire, I didn&apos;t spew the usual garbage about market disruption or technological innovation. Instead, I talked about something revolutionary in finance: actually staying alive long enough to enjoy your success.</span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">We&apos;re talking about building a culture where:</span></span></p>
<ul>
  <li><p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">Mental health isn&apos;t just a buzzword</span></span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">Wellness isn&apos;t something you postpone until retirement</span></span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">Success doesn&apos;t require sacrificing your soul</span></span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">Walking backward through traffic isn&apos;t considered crazy (okay, maybe a little)</span></span></p></li>
</ul>
<p><br /></p>
<h2><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"><strong>The Real Talk About Wall Street Leadership</strong></span></span></h2>
<p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">Look, if you want to read about a Wall Street veteran who admits to learning his best business lessons from acts like shoveling snow and splitting his pants in client meetings, check out the full interview in Authority Magazine. It&apos;s probably the only finance article you&apos;ll read this year that mentions both parasympathetic sighs and mixtapes. </span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">Want more unfiltered wisdom about surviving Wall Street without losing your soul (or your pants)? Grab my book, &quot;How to Succeed on Wall Street and Why You Absolutely Should Not Do It.&quot; Or don&apos;t. I&apos;m not your financial advisor. I am just a guy trying to tell it straight, no chaser.  </span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">P.S. The Playlist for the book Rocks. (yes, I said playlist and shouldn’t all books now come with them?)</span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">Remember: Success isn&apos;t about having all the answers — it&apos;s about being honest enough to admit when you&apos;re as clueless as everyone else, and resilient enough to figure it out anyway. Perspective is a choice and Success is a Consequence. You get to decide what. </span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">I got content, merch, and more. Check out </span></span><u><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OG_X3wMuyjo" target="_blank"><span style="color: rgb(17, 85, 204);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">my Morigin story</span></span></a></u><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"> for a humorous look at how I got my superpowers! </span></span></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA["How to Succeed on Wall Street and Why You Absolutely Should Not Do It" Unmasks Wall Street's Illusions with Candid Insights and Practical Advice]]></title><description><![CDATA[S.A. Thomas combines raw storytelling with practical lessons, guiding professionals through the hidden pitfalls of finance. With humor...]]></description><link>https://www.moronsmemoir.com/post/how-to-succeed-on-wall-street-and-why-you-absolutely-should-not-do-it-unmasks-wall-street-s-illusi</link><guid isPermaLink="false">673917b1948de5818e06ea71</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 22:08:50 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Steven Thomas</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: rgb(14, 16, 26);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">S.A. Thomas combines raw storytelling with practical lessons, guiding professionals through the hidden pitfalls of finance. With humor and brutal honesty, he reveals the personal costs of ambition, emphasizing that true success shouldn’t come at the expense of well-being.</span></span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: rgb(14, 16, 26);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"><strong>November 14, 2024 — FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE. Staten Island, NY —</strong></span></span><span style="color: rgb(14, 16, 26);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"> In his debut book, &quot;How to Succeed on Wall Street and Why You Absolutely Should Not Do It&quot;, author S.A. Thomas offers readers an unfiltered journey through the ups and downs of a Wall Street career, providing an insider&apos;s unique perspective on the financial industry&apos;s closely guarded realities. Launched alongside a video series, &quot;Only Stupid Questions,&quot; filmed across iconic New York City locations, Thomas&apos; book reflects the grit and allure of Wall Street, shedding light on what really happens behind closed doors.</span></span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: rgb(14, 16, 26);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">&quot;My goal with this book goes beyond ego. As I advance in my career, I&apos;m driven to help others heal from the industry&apos;s trauma,&quot; says Thomas. &quot;I&apos;ve worked across every department in finance, and I want readers to see Wall Street for what it truly is beyond the facade. Business is not difficult, but people make it so.&quot;</span></span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: rgb(14, 16, 26);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">Thomas&apos; refreshingly raw approach combines storytelling and practical lessons for navigating high-stakes environments. Through insights on topics like burnout, personal integrity, and the importance of perspective, he offers readers a path to success without compromising their well-being. </span></span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: rgb(14, 16, 26);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">Geared toward professionals eager to understand the hidden pitfalls of the finance industry, &quot;How to Succeed on Wall Street and Why You Absolutely Should Not Do It&quot; serves as both a guide and a warning. Thomas&apos;s Staten Island narrative style, seasoned with humor and brutal honesty, reveals what it takes to succeed and the personal cost that often comes with it. Nobody will say &apos;Fuggedaboutit&apos; to the powerful insight that ambition should never come at the expense of well-being.</span></span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: rgb(14, 16, 26);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">Order &quot;How to Succeed on Wall Street and Why You Absolutely Should Not Do It&quot; today on Amazon, or listen on Audible and iTunes. For more information or to watch the series, visit </span></span><u><a href="http://creativepostures.com" target="_blank"><span style="color: rgb(74, 110, 224);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"><strong>creativepostures.com</strong></span></span></a></u><span style="color: rgb(14, 16, 26);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"><strong>. </strong></span></span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: rgb(14, 16, 26);"><span style="background-color: transparent;"><strong>About The Author: S.A. (Steve) Thomas</strong></span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: rgb(14, 16, 26);"><span style="background-color: transparent;">Thomas&apos;s Wall Street journey spans two decades, from barely getting a foot in the door to closing multi-million-dollar deals while getting his shoes shined. After gaining an insider&apos;s view of the industry&apos;s secrets and survival strategies, he&apos;s spilling the tequila. Known for his wit and candid honesty, Thomas shares practical advice for succeeding in the finance industry without losing your soul. Through his “Real Life Situation Meditations” and “Only Stupid Questions” YouTube series, he helps ambitious professionals avoid the pitfalls that nearly destroyed him. Thomas lives in Staten Island with his family, where he continues gathering wisdom at local pizza joints.</span></span></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Opportunity Knocks - How a Moron Listens]]></title><description><![CDATA[I woke up this damp and rainy Sunday morning to some fantastic news, even though September has yet to end. Two full days of northeastern...]]></description><link>https://www.moronsmemoir.com/post/opportunity-knocks-how-a-moron-listens</link><guid isPermaLink="false">66fc91325a23d590596b29cc</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:20:36 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Steven Thomas</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I woke up this damp and rainy Sunday morning to some fantastic news, even though September has yet to end. Two full days of northeastern rain, you see, has opened up a grand opportunity, which is lubricating the gears of the machine of life- enabling a smoothness of motion I could really use right about now. Today was going to be… complicated. My son Sal had a soccer game and has missed a couple of practices and games due to (insert life excuses here). We all agreed he needed to show up for his team, because that is part of being a teammate.  Coincidentally we are also asked to be in attendance for the Manhattan Thomas’, Jared and Tali- whose beautiful 3month daughter Jewel is to have her naming ceremony.  What a funky cold <u>medina.</u><a href="http://medina.To" target="_blank"> </a><u><a href="http://medina.To" target="_blank">To</a></u> add some urgency, it&apos;s also Jared’s birthday, which he would happily forgo in honor of his daughter. This is the type of guy he is.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>You see, Jared, my forever supporting cousin, has been there – through my thick hair, and now, my thinning spots as well.  When others fall out of my head, he stays – like a yarmulke, to cover up the bald spots. I call him the <em>Most Sincere Thomas</em>, and the list of adjectives doesn’t stop there. He is also a Moron, like me, but somehow his M.I.A. (Moron In Action) always seems sweet, forgivable, and understanding. He has a gift. “<em>Oh, its ok, its Jared’</em> gets thrown around like a baseball from the outfield, nailing the runner trying to make it home.  I would be jealous- or envious, at his ability to get out of some interesting situations- but I am not. I am grateful. Grateful that a younger (cough, cough), more naïve version of a Thomas exists. One whose sincerity drips off of him like the sweat stains under his armpits.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>As I’ve gone through my mid-life awakening, it’s not a crisis I swear! Jared has been there the whole way. He shows up- in person, for a phone call, to take a shvitz, a 1am email, to remind you that sometimes soccer starts at 7am, but mostly to exhibit his number one quality—his sincere caring. He cares in a way that is so foreign to me that it may as well be another language. Well, it is another type of language, and one that may go the way of the dodo bird if we don’t start paying attention- to each other. It’s simply listening, and the man is an expert. What I have been able to learn through the years from Jared, who is also displaying the famous Thomas hearing loss is, that you don’t even need ears to listen. Jared listens empathetically, and most importantly, from his heart. His ability to ego check at the door and be there for people is a superpower of another dimension. When called into action, JT is more calm than a kindergarten teacher. More empathetic than a wise grandmother, and more helpful than an expensive therapist. Super Jared has been a force for good now for 37 years. Positively beaming, he swooped in and married his wonderful wife Tali, and together they created a Jewel.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>What magic is possible when we just listen to create?  When do we give space to each other, and when can we put the other in a place of prestige that our ego’s usually struggle with?  It is a sign of true confidence, and I am grateful to be able to learn from him, even as I blabber on.  I am aware of his sacrifices of time, sleep, and family to support the vision here within. This here website, wouldn’t exist without him. He continues- unwavering and unpaid - to support a vision of healing, for myself and who yet knows.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The rain this morning is truly nourishing. The respite of responsibility allows my Thomas crew to be fully present for his. What a gift. Where I need the tears of the Gods to help with time management, he is gifted with a presence few seem to understand in this day in age. September may be nearing an end, but the lessons of opportunity surround me daily. Todays knock is to ‘Listen’, not with my ears, but with my heart- through patience.  Thank you, Jared, and Happy Birthday my fellow Moron! </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>With Gratitude and a Healing Deafness,</p>
<p>S.A. Thomas</p>
<p>9.29.2024</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Curiosity of Possibility or The Precipice of Remembrance]]></title><description><![CDATA[I wake up to a quiet Saturday morning, and when you have a full house of young children, that is a blessing in itself. “It is the supreme...]]></description><link>https://www.moronsmemoir.com/post/the-curiosity-of-possibility-or-the-precipice-of-remembrance</link><guid isPermaLink="false">66f214ee02912a4ab7ed8d30</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 01:27:54 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Steven Thomas</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I wake up to a quiet Saturday morning, and when you have a full house of young children, that is a blessing in itself.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>“It is the supreme art of the leader to awaken the joy of creative expression and knowledge” -Albert Einstein</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>An old but connected friend continues to show me the mirror of joy, even though it’s cracked. You see, this man IS Joy, as his last name -Gioia, literally translates in Italian to ‘The Bringer of Joy’. I remember as a teen and 20 somethings how he would come around with that smile: always so positive and uplifting. It was unmistakable.  It was that joy that I remember that led me to call him a representative agent in the sweet process of securing a mortgage for a Pennsylvania abode I am looking to complete next week. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Never doubting his qualifications, I reached out after we had been distant from each other for longer than I would like to admit. The man has become very ‘successful’ in his career, made a ton of money, but even from our first re-connection, seemed different.  More Alpha, more Bravado, more – Piss N Vinegar, than I could recall.  I recognize these attributes more than most because of the life I’ve lived. The search and journey to hunt and maintain the hunt, in the form of dollars, is arduous and stressful. It sometimes forces us to release who we are to become who we think we need to be. Love and Compassion yield to Aggressiveness and Disdain- all for the Dolla Dolla Bills Y&apos;all.  And there are plenty of those to chase and keep us busy.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>In my recent dealings with Ryan, I felt his pain, and it is my belief that because I’ve been bitten by that sinister bug in the past, that I can still vividly recall its energy signature. I can see the bullseye that the tick of greed leaves behind.  Given our arrangement, he’s seen my W2s, heard some of my stories and knows a bit about what I’ve been up to. I am validated, in part because of my scars and battle wounds. I am meeting him where he is at, and he knows that I know how lonely he feels. I know he’s hooked on the junk of cents, rather than the potion of sense. I know he doesn’t see an end to the rat race, only the cheese hidden around questionable turns. Nothing is enough, and his existence is grounded in a futility he never even knew he chose.  Now that he is looking around, what can he do? Trapped in a cage he designed meticulously over a 20+year career. I know this because I was there.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>We spend time talking, and inevitably I will blabber on about my story of release; of unlocking my cage. How I was guided towards a future very different from the immediate past that had surrounded me. But not my true past. Not my true self. That self, that came way before the chase for cheese. Well prior to the ugly version of a rat that I splintered into, I was a happy soul, who only cared about spreading joy through THE CURIOSITY OF POSSIBILITY. I am intrigued by this thing called life and it&apos;s always given me energy to move forward.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>When I decided I was done, I stampeded into the abyss. I was broken in many places physically and In need of surgery. I was concussed to the point I could not see straight, and I was emotionally stabbed in places I never knew existed. These are not metaphors. I woke up and found out that healing is possible. Healing is life, and it is an active choice we get to make.  It’s a choice, the same as hurting.  I am forever grateful for the PAIN and HURT because without them- what would I be here to heal? </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>My journey of discovery is one I set for myself. The bullies, the backstabbing, the climbing of the perilous and splintered ladder of success were all choices that I made. Painful choices, mostly made without the deep thought and consideration they deserved. But choices, nonetheless. I own them, and I love them.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>As I hear the vitriol in my friend’s voice, I feel those pains return. Only now, from where my perspective currently sits, I feel sadness. He does not know over the phone that my eyes well, like that water I will access in PA. It’s a community well system, which just seems so perfectly poetic at this moment. He does not know that it hurts ME to see HIM floating in this space. For I know where this path leads.  The good news is, with awareness and choice, it can lead to miracles.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Transmuting energy, as I’ve tried to jibber to Ryan, is a developed skill of intention that requires an abundance of will and practice. I am a novice in this space, yet the amount of traumatic moon rocks that surround me are so plentiful that they allow me to bang into some positions of learning, albeit seemingly accidentally. I am no teacher. I am a friend, and friends share what they can. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>My Joyous friend seems on the precipice of remembrance. He seems ready to forget what does not serve.  Choosing between those is difficult, but very profitable in a way ‘success’ can never be.  I feel gravitated to this journey or pain and healing for reasons I don’t yet get.  I feel strongly that sharing my own vulnerability allows both myself and others the opportunity to heal together.  I am grateful for it all, and as I continue to unlock my own cage of understanding, I hope it helps loosen the locks that others have also created.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Yesterday was Ryan’s birthday and I had not a clue. I know that his joyous mirror still reflects that feeling back to me, and I have been thinking about how I may remember joy within myself, so that I may share it with others. The more I think I&apos;ve been helping him, the more I have somehow turned to helping myself.  Karmic circles of invisibility.  Some mirrors aren’t brown, they are just a little dusty, and that can be easy enough to clean. Thank God for that.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Come back like Gioia, wearing the 4-5.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Ryan can be reached at Ryan Gioia Senior Loan Officer A-M-S Mortgage Services 201-566-7054 direct # or <a href="mailto:ryan@amsmtg.com" target="_blank">ryan@amsmtg.com</a></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>With Gratitude and Awareness,</p>
<p>S.A.Thomas</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tuning for the Equinox]]></title><description><![CDATA[I wake up on this calm Sunday morning in September, realizing it is also the fall Equinox as well.  A good friend is releasing an album...]]></description><link>https://www.moronsmemoir.com/post/one-note-on-the-equinox</link><guid isPermaLink="false">66f1d76c88d6cd245ec1f618</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 21:02:46 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/158249_14c2227b99814644a058cd5199f7f1b9~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Steven Thomas</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/158249_14c2227b99814644a058cd5199f7f1b9~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>I wake up on this calm Sunday morning in September, realizing it is also the fall Equinox as well.  A good friend is releasing an album today and I am excited to be able to listen to it. I believe this day was chosen because of its significance as a balanced day, one of four sacred ones we get each year.  Balanced for the moment, I will always remember that I met my wife on the summer equinox which clearly tells me that special moments are very possible on these unique days. The song of life carries many notes, and the one that came before this carried with it a tone I cannot forget. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Yesterday, a wonderful man named Sam came to tune our piano. The piano was a gift from a dear friend who moved to Florida, and I had assumed it hadn’t been tuned in a long time. A couple of years ago I (we) moved it, surely knocking some of its tonality out of sorts. Sam tuned this piano by ear only, with no additional substantial equipment.  Well, except for skill and expertise of course. I was thoroughly impressed by this art of improving art. I had assumed he would show up with some sort of machine, technology, or at the very least calibration equipment to help the process, but as Sam explained, if you worked for Steinway, you had to tune by ear or you didn’t work for Steinway any longer. There was a specific formula that the founders had come up with and that was to be respected if you were to procure employment. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Did you know that the Piano industry was once the biggest in America back during the turn of the 20th century? Before the automobile industry took us to new carbureted heights , pianos were  the IT thing to have, and as Sam said, there were something like 50 piano makers – just in New  York alone.  Now there may be 5 in all of America. A dying breed, lost to the future of here and now. As I watched the past, Sam meticulously played with the hammers, the little wooden felt tipped mechanisms that hit the strings, thus creating the sounds. He continuously hit keys, at different lengths, speeds, and intervals. I was stupefied. He mentioned that he was counting frequency and he was just basically doing simple mathematics. Perhaps, I am the simpleton in this situation. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>What I was witnessing was more than just math. Sam had a distinct touch- not just of the ivories, but of the connections between his affect and the sounds effect. I was watching a master at his craft. Sam had some sort of ribbon that he tied to the chords, and a few other hand tools which seemed more likely to be found on a carpenter than on a piano tuner. He continuously went up and down the piano, because as he explained, there is a relationship between all the keys and tightening one part of the instrument too much at a time can cause the entirety to fall out of tune.  The best analogy I can muster is that if you tighten your sneakers too much at the bottom, then the top never quite feels right. That and your toes go numb.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Is there a parallel between walking and tuning a piano? Sometimes I know I can feel ‘out of Whack’, or ‘out of sorts’. Does that mean my internal tuning is off? Watching Sam was like seeing into the past, and for a while I saw by closing my eyes and listening. What were these frequencies he was counting? What told him exactly when he had gotten it right? At a certain point I had to give up trying to figure it out, a welcomed theme in my life right now.  So I just let it be.  I closed my eyes again and drifted off into a sort of Alpha brain state as he continued tuning. I wonder if I could tune myself? I wonder what strings inside of me need tightening and I wonder if sometimes I am just strung too tightly? </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The chakra system seems to also resonate with frequency, which is to say they all have their own unique notes. Together they harmonize and what becomes of this harmony is the song of silence that resonates out, mostly without our ever being aware. I had known the low end of the piano, the bass notes were out of tune. As he worked though, I could tell very easily that the middle and upper ranges were also needing his mechanical skill. As he continued to hammer on, the notes kept sounding more pure than they previously had.  Funny aside, a beautifully crafted instrument such as this 1970’s Wurlitzer could have been so ‘off’ without anyone noticing. How off can we be in life, without ever having a clue?  Sam recommends tuning a piano every 6 months, how long have I been out of tune?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Sam explained to me a bit more about the architecture of the piano, but without googling it again, it would be nearly impossible for me to regurgitate.  My novice take is, every piece plays a part and each piece is essential to the whole. One string can have an outsized effect on all that surround it.  Sam mentioned that the strings also had ‘memories’ and I chuckled, of course they do. We never forget the frequencies of our past. From the top strings made of steel and as thin as a pin, down to the bottom ones vigorously wrapped in copper for depth and pulled in the opposite direction for length – as Mr. Steinway designed, all of these strings serve a distinct purpose. Alone they are worthless- together they are symphonic. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>As Sam was finishing up, this wonderfully calm and well spoken man told me of how, just out of LaGuardia and City College of Music back in the 60s, he had bills and needed a job so he went to apply to a starter company, Baldwin Pianos.  This inferior maker would be a good place to start for Sam but upon interviewing he was quickly shoo-flied away without even being given an opportunity. He decided he would shoot his shot and try to get a gig at Steinway, America&apos;s premier Piano maker.  Fortuitous timing and preparation gave Sam a lucky shot to interview. <em>Ok kid, tune this piano</em>. So Sam sat down and tuned the piano. Just after, a short stocky man he had not seen previously sat down and started tickling the keys. <em>The kid’s alright, Hire him. </em>That’s what Mr. Steinway said to the hiring manager and the rest is, as they say, history.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Sam’s natural ability to fine tune was shaped with the help of his childhood- specifically his mother who was a music teacher.  He knew from a young age how things should sound and was constantly finding his own tune.  He knew how math worked one could say. He was astute enough to understand the balance of tone, and how adjusting just one string could have far reaching effects on the instrument. Today, on this Equinox Sunday, which I believe represents an Early balance of which I understand very little, I am grateful to have had this experience. I am awestruck at the art of Organic Talent that still exists on this planet, and I am moved to memorialize it in my humble way. I too wish to be tuned like a piano, and I wonder how those skills can be developed so that my instrument may sound as good as this old piano, one note touching all. One key to unlock them all. Thank you Sam, and thank you Opportunity. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>What would you do if I sang out of tune, would you stand up and walk out on me? </p>
<p>Lend me your ear and I’ll sing you a song, I will try not sing out of key…</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>‘TUNE IT AGAIN, SAM.”  Can be reached at  <a href="mailto:Persam1197@aol.com" target="_blank">Persam1197@aol.com</a> or on his cell @ 845-480-4217</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>With Gratitude and Delight,</p>
<p>S.A. Thomas</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>